The SQL keywords you learned for querying
are harmless as they make no changes to your
existing data.
Now, we will cover some keywords that do change
data.
Changing data can be both good and bad.
It’s good in the sense of using keywords
to add, change, and remove data, but we want
to make sure only those who know how to use
these keywords can.
The main reason: SQL doesn’t feature an
undo button.
Once you change data, it’s changed.
Our next goal in working with queries is to
insert data into an entity.
There are two basic ways to do this: We can
either copy records from one table to another
or insert records manually or from a data
source such as an app.
In the first example, we see a query that
inserts all the records from the BikeRepairs
table into the BikeRepairsTest table.
I will execute this query, and the records
from the BikeRepairs table have been copied
into the BikeRepairsTest table.
INSERT INTO with a SELECT is used to copy
records from one table to an existing table.
But, what if you want to copy records from
an existing table into a new table.
A SELECT INTO statement will make this happen.
Take a look at this statement that selects
everything into a BikeRepairsArchive table
from the BikeRepairs table.
The BikeRepairsArchive table does not yet
exist.
However, once I select and execute this statement,
the table will exist with the records from
the BikeRepairs table.
SELECT INTO is a great option to use when
one wants to make a copy of an entire table,
including the table's structure.